Fariz Kamal

Thousand Oaks, CA.

269 993 1885 farizbin.kamal@wmich.edu LinkedIn Profile GitHub Profile

Seasoned computer science graduate with a specialized background in automation industry focused on Pharmaceutical and Biotech Industry with experiences in Delta V Distributed Control Systems (DCS), Rockwell Programmable Logic Controllers (PLC), Human Machine Interface (HMI), Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition Systems (SCADA) and ABB robotics with deeply committed to maintaining a strong work ethic and passion about innovative problem-solving to drive efficiency and excellence.

## Experiences

Software Developer/Information Systems Engineer Co Op

RoviSys, Thousand Oaks, CA – July 2023 – PRESENT

- At RoviSys, I developed internal applications at RoviSys tailored for systems engineers to convert DeltaV DCS data into PI Tags, resulting in a 31% faster performance and 14% improved memory efficiency and updates like adding multiple tag endings in the PI Tags.
- I delved into PI systems and explored servers for data point extraction. This critical undertaking enhanced our understanding of machines in the automation industry and allowed us to analyze various parameters across numerous vertical markets, ultimately driving business insights and efficiencies.

## Helpdesk Technician

Office of Information Technology at WMU, Kalamazoo MI: January 2023 - July 2023

- TCP/IP, DNS, and DHCP protocols were used to diagnose and troubleshoot a complicated technical issue relating to network connectivity, which allowed the entire team to get back to work right away.
- Directed changes to the active directory domain setup, produced technical documentation and functional specs, and managed change for them. During this training, I was able to strengthen my domain management and technical documentation abilities, assuring the organization's seamless operations.

# **Tech Support Intern**

Kalamazoo Public Library, Kalamazoo, Michigan: September 2022 - June 2023

- Implemented and supported business systems solutions that meet or exceed customers' and internal business partners' business requirements for assigned sector within the library.
- Supported and ensured a quality delivery of a predefined IT solution as selected to support a business need. The IT solution delivery includes effective system setup, training, implementation and post implementation support of the predefined IT solution such as an Order management system for Idea Lab, an existing client site resulting in 30% more production of 3D materials.

#### Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Western Michigan University

Graduation: August 2023

CGPA: 3.11

# **Undergrad Research**

IOT Security in MQTT Protocol and it's vulnerabilities and analysis of datasets of attacks and benign behaviors.

Supervisor: Dr. Shameek Bhattacharjee. (Assistant Professor, Department of Computer Science, Western Michigan University)

# **Projects**

**Senior Design**: Implementation of District Boundary Map on Level Data Connect Extension. Modified map using mapbox API for every query. And implementation of shapefiles for Boundaries. [React.js and Typescript]

**GSN Model Execution and XML Parser for a decision making f1/10 race car module**: Implemented an XML parser to conclude a decision to be executed by the module. [Java]

Created a software to replicate Linux's word count tool with efficient use of a buffer and an array of structs. [C]

Developed an application to support systems engineers at RoviSys to deal with intricate machine data and perform services from Delta V to turn into PI Tags for use in Pharmaceuticals and Biotech Industry. [Python]

## Education

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, C, R, JavaScript, PHP
- Software & Tools: Veeva QMS, Veeva Quality Vault, Vue.js, Spring Boot, Tableau, OSIsoft PI System, AWS, MuleSoft
- Methodologies: Scrum, Business Analysis, API Integration, Requirement Engineering, Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC)
- Databases: SQL,
- Automation: DeltaV DCS, Rockwell PLCs, Siemens WinCC, ABB RobotStudio